András Gémes

Summary

Embedded software engineer with 7 years of experience and a strong interest in cybersecurity, with hands-on experience in malware analysis and reverse engineering (e.g., ransomware, loaders and botnets). Certified in Sec+, CASP+/SecX, CEH, IMBT and PMAT. Looking to apply my technical expertise and security skills in a malware analyst or reverse engineer role.

Work experience

Rust Embedded Software Engineer

Feb 2023 - Present

HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

- Developing Rust and assembly tests for the Rust compiler
- · Hardening the Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Creating customer-facing C and Rust examples for real-time operating system (RTOS) and bare-metal environments

Embedded Software Engineer

May 2018 – Jan 2023

Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary

- Configured, automated and evaluated Static Application Security Testing (SAST) using PC-lint and Clang-Tidy tools
- Configured memory, real-time operating system (RTOS) and Controller Area Network (CAN) software modules
- Integrated Advanced Driver Assistance Systems (ADAS) software across various Electronic Control Units (ECUs)

Skills

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (ARM64/AArch64, AMD64/x86-64), Bash

Malware analysis (static): Ghidra, IDA, capa, YARA, DiE, dnSpy, readelf, objdump

Malware analysis (dynamic): x64dbg, VirtualBox, Qiling, Sysinternals, Regshot, Frida, GDB, eBPF, strace

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, AURIX, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

Certifications

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH, Invoke RE IMBT and TCM Security PMAT

Relevant projects

- ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches to Ghidra, focusing on the FunctionID and BSim features
- ghidra-scripts: implementing custom Ghidra scripts to support malware analysis
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- shadow-shell: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

Education

MSc in Mechatronics Engineering

Feb 2016 - June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

BSc in Mechatronics Engineering

Sept 2012 - Jan 2016

University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary

Continuous education

I am actively learning on Maldev Academy and TryHackMe, reading Blue Fox: Arm Assembly and managing my homelab.